# **Zach Cohen**

(480) 444-8097 **zachtylercohen@gmail.com** 

My education and practical work experience has been focused on how we interact with the world around us. Through design and research, I am mindful of the entire lifecycle of a product and its business impact. My goal is to help create products and shape experiences that have a positive impact on people's lives.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Integrate Inc.**, Phoenix, AZ— Product Designer

MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

- Helped establish a Design System to guide best practices and overall progression.
- Led an initiative to improve research practices in design and product.
- Partnered with product management to conduct discovery and define software features.
- Led design, user research, and product-informed strategy for several product development teams.
- Prototyped, user tested, and worked with engineering to implement and ship designs.

#### **InEight**, Scottsdale, AZ— Interaction Designer (Contract)

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Translated design vision established through research to update legacy products.
- Worked closely with product and development teams to add and refine product features.
- Led user experience optimization alongside key stakeholders and product management.

## **Nucleus Marketing Lab,** Phoenix, AZ— *User Researcher* (Contract)

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

- Helped recognize user behavior and re-frame product development goals through qualitative and quantitative research and analysis.
- Used accumulated data to help provide brand strategy insight for both regional and national companies.

### a verynice design studio, Los Angeles, CA— UX Strategy Intern

JANUARY 2017 - MAY 2017

 Worked closely with the lead strategist to develop MVPs and design artifacts for startups and non-profit organizations.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Designlab**, Remote— *User Experience Design certificate*

GRADUATED MAY 2018

Over 480 hours of coursework, more than 100 hands-on exercises, a total of 4 portfolio projects, community and mentor-based interaction.

## **Woodbury University,** Burbank, CA— B.A. Interdisciplinary Studies, Psychology and Interior Architecture Emphases

GRADUATED MAY 2017

AIAS (American Institute of Architectural Students), IIDA (International Interior Design Association), Zone V Photography Club.

#### **SKILLS**

Qualitative Research

Quantitative Research

**Usability Testing** 

High Fidelity Prototyping

**Experience Mapping** 

User Interface Design

Information Architecture

Adobe Creative Suite

Sketch

InVision

Framer

HTML/CSS

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### **Emergency Design**

Collective: Working to provide responses to urgent public health crises through multidisciplinary collaboration, design, and research

Conducted research and prototyping in August 2020 for a community project to address K-3 students learning at home during COVID-19.